<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Android-Qgis on QField - Efficient field work built for QGIS</title><link>https://qfield.org/categories/android-qgis/</link><description>Recent content in Android-Qgis on QField - Efficient field work built for QGIS</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 06:31:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://qfield.org/categories/android-qgis/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Powerful and gentle QField 1.8 Selma sneaked in</title><link>https://qfield.org/2021/02/24/powerful-and-gentle-qfield-1-8-selma-sneaked-in/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 06:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2021/02/24/powerful-and-gentle-qfield-1-8-selma-sneaked-in/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Get fieldwork smoothly and nimbly done despite the ice and snow outside. Collect accurate data with freehand digitizing and improved form widgets, use the data from your external GNSS receivers without any third-party apps and enjoy the pleasant usability of QField 1.8 Selma.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year started off hi-speed for us. There&amp;rsquo;s been already a lot of coding, designing and teaching, and we&amp;rsquo;ve thrown ourselves into these things we love to do. And we published another QField release last week that I completely forgot to announce in this blog. But here it is. It&amp;rsquo;s QField 1.8, Selma. And it&amp;rsquo;s packed with cool features.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 1.7 Rockies hits the stage</title><link>https://qfield.org/2020/10/20/qfield-1-7-rockies-hits-the-stage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 07:26:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2020/10/20/qfield-1-7-rockies-hits-the-stage/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Be ready for the cold weather with a smooth coordinate search, filters in the value relation widget, fancy new QML and HTML widgets, enhanced geometry editing functionalities and an expandable legend. Right when Autumn starts, QField 1.7 Rockies hits the stage.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As usual get it now on the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ch.opengis.qfield" target="_blank" rel="noopener">play store&lt;/a> or on &lt;a href="https://github.com/opengisch/QField/releases" target="_blank" rel="noopener">github&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The days are getting shorter and the wind blows colder. It&amp;rsquo;s always good to be in a good company outside while getting your mapping work done. QField will be your reliable companion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 1.6 is out!</title><link>https://qfield.org/2020/08/18/qfield-1-6-is-out/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2020/08/18/qfield-1-6-is-out/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Editing multiple features at the same time, support for stylus pens, dynamic configuration of image names and much more.&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>QField 1.6 Qinling 秦岭 comes packed with awesome new features and an improved user experience.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have been very busy over the last few months working on a new and shiny QField release. We have added many new features that increase efficiency on the field or allow for new workflows. In parallel, we have also been working on ironing out a series of issues and improving the overall user experience to make the app as pleasurable to use as possible. The result is QField 1.6 which has been published now.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 1.0 is here</title><link>https://qfield.org/2019/03/28/qfield-1-0-is-here/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 15:34:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2019/03/28/qfield-1-0-is-here/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="lets-get-straight-to-the-point">Let&amp;rsquo;s get straight to the point&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s official, QField for QGIS 1.0 is out!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Get it while it’s hot on the Playstore ( &lt;a href="https://qfield.org/get" target="_blank" rel="noopener">qfield.org/get&lt;/a>) or on &lt;a href="https://github.com/opengisch/QField/releases" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are incredibly pleased and proud of just having released such a jewel and are convinced that, thanks to all its features and conscious design choices, QField will make your field digitizing work much more efficient and pleasant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Packed with loads of useful features like online and offline features digitizing, geometry and attributes editing, attribute search, powerful forms, theme switching, GPS support, camera integration and much more, QField is the powerful tool for those who need to edit on the go and would like to avoid standing in the swamp with a laptop or paper charts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField RC5 - Last call for testing</title><link>https://qfield.org/2019/03/14/qfield-rc5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 11:50:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2019/03/14/qfield-rc5/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are really happy to announce the fifth and (hopefully) last 1.0 release candidate in QField&amp;rsquo;s history! This means that QField 1.0 is closer than ever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Get it while it&amp;rsquo;s hot on the Playstore ( &lt;a href="https://qfield.org/get" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://qfield.org/get&lt;/a>) or on &lt;a href="https://github.com/opengisch/QField/releases" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to all the feedback by the fantastic community we were able to fix plenty of bugs, address performance issues and even add some super cool new features.&lt;/p>














&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://i2.wp.com/new.opengis.ch/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/fileselector.jpg?fit=541%2C1024&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 
 
 >
 
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Among the new features, the most important is the flashy new file selector with favorite directories (long press on a folder to add it to the favorites and longpress on the favorites list to remove it) and an automatic list of the last three opened projects that will save you heaps of time while looking for your projects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Year's present - QField 1.0 RC1</title><link>https://qfield.org/2019/01/08/qfield-1-0-rc1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 06:59:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2019/01/08/qfield-1-0-rc1/</guid><description>&lt;p>It was a long and winding road but we are very excited to announce the general availability of QField 1.0 Release Candidate 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Packed with loads of useful features like online and offline features digitizing, geometry and attributes editing, attribute search, powerful forms, theme switching, GPS support, camera integration and much more, QField is the powerful tool for those who need to edit on the go and would like to avoid standing in the swamp with a laptop or paper charts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Year&amp;#039;s present - QField 1.0 RC1</title><link>https://qfield.org/2019/01/08/qfield-1-0-rc1-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 06:59:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2019/01/08/qfield-1-0-rc1-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>It was a long and winding road but we are very excited to announce the general availability of QField 1.0 Release Candidate 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Packed with loads of useful features like online and offline features digitizing, geometry and attributes editing, attribute search, powerful forms, theme switching, GPS support, camera integration and much more, QField is the powerful tool for those who need to edit on the go and would like to avoid standing in the swamp with a laptop or paper charts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField for Android 5</title><link>https://qfield.org/2015/12/01/qfield-for-android-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 13:44:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2015/12/01/qfield-for-android-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>











 



&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://developer.android.com/images/brand/en%5Fapp%5Frgb%5Fwo%5F45.png" alt="QField app on Google Play" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 width="129"
 
 style="ZgotmplZ">
 
 
 &lt;figcaption class="figure-caption text-center">QField app on Google Play&lt;/figcaption>
 
&lt;/figure>












 



&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://developer.android.com/images/brand/en%5Fapp%5Frgb%5Fwo%5F45.png" alt="QField Karma edition app on Google Play" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 width="129"
 
 style="ZgotmplZ">
 
 
 &lt;figcaption class="figure-caption text-center">QField Karma edition app on Google Play&lt;/figcaption>
 
&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s done, finally we managed to get rid of Ministro so that we finally can say, QField runs on any android from 4.0.3 (ICS). This makes as of today (according to &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/about/dashboards/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">google&lt;/a>) 96% of the android installations worldwide. Eventually we want to settle to 4.3 (JB) as minimum to allow us using certain features and avoiding &lt;a href="https://github.com/opengisch/QField/issues/6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">one known issue&lt;/a>, but for now it would mean cutting of another 25% of the users.
&lt;strong>So as of today it is: 4.0.3 (Ice cream sandwich API 15) is the required minimal Android version to run QField and Android 4.3 (Jelly Bean API 18) is the suggested minimal version.&lt;/strong>
We tested with 4.4, 5.0.1 and 5.1 but we haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to get our hands on an Android 6 so if you can, let us know how it works.
But adding support for android 5 isn&amp;rsquo;t the only great news, during the process we also:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField in the wild</title><link>https://qfield.org/2015/06/15/qfield-in-the-wild/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 12:05:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2015/06/15/qfield-in-the-wild/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://developer.android.com/images/brand/en%5Fapp%5Frgb%5Fwo%5F45.png" alt="QField app on Google Play" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 width="129"
 
 style="ZgotmplZ">
 
 
 &lt;figcaption class="figure-caption text-center">QField app on Google Play&lt;/figcaption>
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.paypal.com/en_US/i/scr/pixel.gif" alt="">&lt;/p>












 



&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://developer.android.com/images/brand/en%5Fapp%5Frgb%5Fwo%5F45.png" alt="QField Karma edition app on Google Play" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 width="129"
 
 style="ZgotmplZ">
 
 
 &lt;figcaption class="figure-caption text-center">QField Karma edition app on Google Play&lt;/figcaption>
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>QField Experimental is out, after a couple of months of requirements gathering, private early alpha testing and foremost tons of  emails requesting access to the testes group we decided today to put the current BETA version in the playstore. This means that from now on you can install QField just like any other android app by using the playstore.
It is important to remember that QField is still beta and thus it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have all the features we want yet. Notably, &lt;em>there is no digitizing, due to a bug in android, Android 5 (Lollipop) is currently not supported (android 4.3 and 4.4 are suggested) and for now you need to manually copy the projects and data from the desktop to your device.&lt;/em>
QField is an Open Source project led by OPENGIS.ch LLC, more &lt;a href="https://qfield.org/android-gis/qfield/">information&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://qfield.opengis.ch/repo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">source code&lt;/a> and a possibility to donate to the project can be found on the &lt;a href="https://qfield.org/android-gis/qfield/">QField page&lt;/a> (preferred) or by buying the QField for &lt;a href="https://qfield.opengis.ch/karma" target="_blank" rel="noopener">QGIS Karma edition app&lt;/a>.
Also if you need a specific feature, &lt;a href="https://qfield.org/contact/">contact us&lt;/a> to sponsor its development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QGIS Mobile 0.2 Demo</title><link>https://qfield.org/2015/01/11/qgis-mobile-0-2-demo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 19:41:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2015/01/11/qgis-mobile-0-2-demo/</guid><description>&lt;p>QField (formerly known as QGIS Mobile) is a touch optimized interface for field work developed by OPENGIS.ch. It is with great pleasure the we want to share with you the demo video of version 0.2.
Since the project is going to be one of our core projects, we set up a dedicated &lt;a href="https://qfield.org/android-gis/qgis-mobile/" title="QGIS mobile">page here&lt;/a>.
The &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/116231850" target="_blank" rel="noopener">QGIS mobile 0.2&lt;/a> video demonstrates some basic functionality like navigation, feature identification and attribute editing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The performance is affected by android&amp;rsquo;s video recording software. In reality animaitons look fluent and the interface feels snappy.
Demo performed on a Galaxy Note 8.0 with Android 4.4.4 (CM11).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happy new year to the power of two!</title><link>https://qfield.org/2015/01/08/happy-new-year-to-the-power-of-two/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 12:17:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2015/01/08/happy-new-year-to-the-power-of-two/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the first time we at OPENGIS.ch can celebrate with 2 people, Marco Bernasocchi and Matthias Kuhn both experienced QGIS developers and holders of a Master degree in GIScience.
After having worked individually in the last years, we have realized that there is a huge potential for us to join our knowledge - because the whole is greater than the sum of its parts. This is why starting from January 1st, 2015 we are working together as OPENGIS.ch LLC.
Marco is the creator of QGIS for Android, has a strong background in python and web applications development and is core committer of the the award-winning InaSafe project.
Matthias is an active QGIS core committer with a long history in developing in a wide variety of programming languages and areas from embedded systems to server services.
We both are strong believers in open source software and are convinced that developing in the public is a big win for everybody.
Among other projects, we are currently working on QGIS Mobile. A touch optimized interface for field work, based on the QGIS libraries. Make sure you keep an eye on this project as it is in its infancy but growing very fast.
If you have a use-case for it and would like to support its development don’t hesitate contacting us. We will happily provide you with a preview version.
[embed]https://vimeo.com/116231850[/embed]
We are are also available for helping you with any idea and project you might have and to give ad-hoc courses that cover topics related to (Q)GIS and programming.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>