<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scripts on QField - Efficient field work built for QGIS</title><link>https://qfield.org/categories/scripts/</link><description>Recent content in Scripts on QField - Efficient field work built for QGIS</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 05:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://qfield.org/categories/scripts/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Offline WMS - Benchmarking raster formats for QField</title><link>https://qfield.org/2020/06/09/offline-wms-benchmarking-raster-formats-for-qfield/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 05:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2020/06/09/offline-wms-benchmarking-raster-formats-for-qfield/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-are-we-looking-for">What are we looking for?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We would like to use WMS offline on QField. For that, we need to figure out what is the best way to get a raster from a WMS and which format is the most efficient (size and performance).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll show you is how to generate the ideal raster file from a WMS and the results of our efficiency tests for the the different raster formats.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL back end solution for quality assurance and data archive</title><link>https://qfield.org/2018/01/08/postgresql-back-end-solution-for-quality-assurance-and-data-archive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 06:06:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2018/01/08/postgresql-back-end-solution-for-quality-assurance-and-data-archive/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;em>Did you know that the possibilities to make a full QGIS back end solution for quality assurance and archiving in PostgreSQL are immense? SQL has it&amp;rsquo;s well known limitations, but with a little bit creativity you can make quite nice solutions just using triggers and rules. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll explain what we did lately based on a project with a customer. He needed to assure the consistency of data but still give his employees the possibility of a fast feeding of the data collected on the field to the database. Another request was to keep every status of the data with the information about the changes (archiving).&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>
It&amp;rsquo;s always the question, where to put the logical part of the solution. QGIS is quite powerful with constraints, but the undeniable advantage of a back end solution is, that you can use any front end - no matter what configuration you have on QGIS or what Feature Manipulation Engine (FME) you use - without influencing the guarantee of data validity.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>