<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Press-Release on QField - Efficient field work built for QGIS</title><link>https://qfield.org/tags/press-release/</link><description>Recent content in Press-Release on QField - Efficient field work built for QGIS</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:01:18 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://qfield.org/tags/press-release/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>QField receives prestigious recognition as a digital public good from the Digital Public Goods Alliance</title><link>https://qfield.org/2024/06/06/qfield-receives-prestigious-recognition-as-a-digital-public-good-from-the-digital-public-goods-alliance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:28:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2024/06/06/qfield-receives-prestigious-recognition-as-a-digital-public-good-from-the-digital-public-goods-alliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>We are thrilled to announce that the&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/best-of-swiss-apps/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best of Swiss Apps&lt;/a> &lt;strong>Enterprise winner 2022, QField, has been officially recognized as a Digital Public Good by the UN-endorsed&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://digitalpublicgoods.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Digital Public Goods Alliance&lt;/a> &lt;strong>. This prestigious recognition highlights QField’s significant contributions to six key Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs): SDG 6 (Clean Water and Sanitation), SDG 9 (Industry, Innovation, and Infrastructure), SDG 11 (Sustainable Cities and Communities), SDG 13 (Climate Action), SDG 15 (Life on Land), and SDG 16 (Peace, Justice, and Strong Institutions). The “Swiss Made Software” QField is the leading fieldwork application with almost 1 Million downloads worldwide.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField collected data crucial in disaster relief after Tonga’s volcanic eruption</title><link>https://qfield.org/2022/02/02/qfield-data-crucial-in-disaster-relief-after-tongas-volcanic-eruption/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 06:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2022/02/02/qfield-data-crucial-in-disaster-relief-after-tongas-volcanic-eruption/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>For once, it&amp;rsquo;s not an app from the Silicon Valley, but from Laax in the Swiss Alps that made the news. By publishing QField as an open-source app, OPENGIS.ch allows companies, organisations and even countries without the necessary financial means to have the opportunity to benefit from this important data collection app. And it is being used: Over half a million downloads have already been achieved. Now, since the volcanic eruption in Tonga on 15 January 2022, the app of the small Laax-based company is playing a not-unimportant role in disaster response planning.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>