<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Qfield-Highlights on QField - Efficient field work built for QGIS</title><link>https://qfield.org/categories/qfield-highlights/</link><description>Recent content in Qfield-Highlights on QField - Efficient field work built for QGIS</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:46:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://qfield.org/categories/qfield-highlights/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>QField 3.6 “Gondwana”: Locking on greatness</title><link>https://qfield.org/2025/06/03/qfield-3-6-gondwana-locking-on-greatness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 07:46:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2025/06/03/qfield-3-6-gondwana-locking-on-greatness/</guid><description>&lt;p>Building on top of the last release which introduced background tracking, this development cycle focused on polishing functionalities and building on top of preexisting features. The variety of improvements is sure to make our diverse user base and community excited to upgrade to QField 3.6.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="main-highlights">Main highlights&lt;/h2>














&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://qfield.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/splash.png" alt="" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 
 
 >
 
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>One of the most noticeable improvement in this version is the addition of “map preview rendering”. &lt;strong>QField now renders partial map content immediately beyond the edge of the screen&lt;/strong>, offering a much nicer experience when panning around as well as zooming in and out. Long-time QGIS users will recognise the behaviour, and we’re delighted to bring this experience to the field&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1 Million Downloads: QField's Big Milestone</title><link>https://qfield.org/2025/05/29/1-million-downloads-qfields-big-milestone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 12:16:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2025/05/29/1-million-downloads-qfields-big-milestone/</guid><description>&lt;p>🚀 QField has officially hit &lt;strong>1 million downloads&lt;/strong> – thanks to &lt;strong>you!&lt;/strong> 🎉&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s not beat around the bush: QField has hit &lt;strong>1+ million downloads&lt;/strong>. What started as an ambitious open-source project has transformed into &lt;strong>a global tool that&amp;rsquo;s changing how professionals collect spatial data in the field&lt;/strong>. This big milestone is the result of years of dedication, with over 50,000 hours invested by our team. Our GeoNinjas contributed 14% of QGIS, while also driving open-source projects like &lt;em>ModelBaker&lt;/em> and &lt;em>SwissLocator&lt;/em>.Thank you for making GIS nerds the &lt;strong>unsung heroes of fieldwork everywhere.&lt;/strong> Here&amp;rsquo;s to changing the world, one field at a time!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 3.5 “Fangorn”: Background tracking a reality!</title><link>https://qfield.org/2025/03/04/qfield-3-5-fangorn-background-tracking-a-reality/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 05:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2025/03/04/qfield-3-5-fangorn-background-tracking-a-reality/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let’s not bury the lead here: the long-awaited capability to track position while QField is in the background or the device is locked has arrived in this brand-new version of QField. This feels like a magical moment, so we settled for a fantastical forest for our release name.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="main-highlights">Main highlights&lt;/h2>














&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://qfield.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/splash.png" alt="" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 
 
 >
 
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>As highlighted above, QField 3.5 has unlocked &lt;strong>background position tracking&lt;/strong> on the Android platform. This allows users to keep track of their positions even as they put QField in the background to conduct other tasks on their devices. It also means that tracking has become far more battery efficient, as users can lock/suspend their phones and tablets for long periods while QField continues to collect and track positions. On top of it all, this will work out of the book with internal GNSS as well as external high-precision GNSS devices.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 3.4 “Ebo”: Geofencing and processing out of the box</title><link>https://qfield.org/2024/10/08/qfield-3-4-ebo-geofencing-and-processing-out-of-the-box/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 04:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2024/10/08/qfield-3-4-ebo-geofencing-and-processing-out-of-the-box/</guid><description>&lt;p>QField 3.4 is out, and it won’t disappoint. It has tons of new features that continue to push the limits of what users can do in the field.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="main-highlights">Main highlights&lt;/h2>














&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://qfield.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/34.png" alt="" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 
 
 >
 
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>A new &lt;strong>geofencing framework&lt;/strong> has landed, enabling users to configure QField behaviors in relation to geofenced areas and user positioning. Geofenced areas are defined at the project-level and shaped by polygons from a chosen vector layer. The three available geofencing behaviours in this new release are:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Supercharge your fieldwork with QField's project and app-wide plugins</title><link>https://qfield.org/2024/06/18/supercharge-your-fieldwork-with-qfields-project-and-app-wide-plugins/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 04:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2024/06/18/supercharge-your-fieldwork-with-qfields-project-and-app-wide-plugins/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This blog post will introduce QField’s brand new plugin framework and walk through the creation of a plugin to support bird watchers in need of a quick way to digitize photos of spotted birds onto a point vector layer.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-plugin-framework-is-born">A plugin framework is born!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As &lt;a href="https://qfield.org/2024/06/11/qfield-3-3-darien-it-is-just-the-beginning/">announced recently&lt;/a>, QField now empowers users through a brand new &lt;a href="https://docs.qfield.org/how-to/plugins/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">plugin framework&lt;/a> allowing for simple customization on the way the application behaves or looks all the way through to creating completely new functionalities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 3.3 “Darién”: It is just the beginning</title><link>https://qfield.org/2024/06/11/qfield-3-3-darien-it-is-just-the-beginning/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 04:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2024/06/11/qfield-3-3-darien-it-is-just-the-beginning/</guid><description>&lt;p>QField 3.3 has been released, and with it, we are proud to introduce a brand new plugin framework that empowers users to customize and add completely new functionalities to their favourite field application. That’s on top of a bunch of new features and improvements added during this development cycle. What preceded this moment was just the beginning!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="main-highlights">Main highlights&lt;/h2>














&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://qfield.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/33splash.png" alt="" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 
 
 >
 
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>One of the biggest feature additions of this version is a brand new drawing tool that allows users to sketch out important details over captured photos or annotate drawing templates. This was a highly requested feature, which we are delighted to bring to all supported platforms (Android, iOS, Windows, macOS, and, of course, Linux) with the financial support of the &lt;a href="http://qgis.ch" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Swiss QGIS user group&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 3.2 “Congo”: Making your life easier</title><link>https://qfield.org/2024/04/04/qfield-3-2-congo-making-your-life-easier/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 07:58:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2024/04/04/qfield-3-2-congo-making-your-life-easier/</guid><description>&lt;p>Focused on stability and usability improvements, most users will find something to celebrate in QField 3.2&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="main-highlights">&lt;strong>Main highlights&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>














&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://qfield.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/qfield32.png" alt="" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 
 
 >
 
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>This new release introduces &lt;strong>project-defined tracking sessions, which are automatically activated when the project is loaded&lt;/strong>. Defined while setting up and tweaking a project on QGIS, these sessions permit the automated tracking of device positions without taking any action in QField beyond opening the project itself. This liberates field users from remembering to launch a session on app launch and lowers the knowledge required to collect such data. For more details, please read the &lt;a href="https://docs.qfield.org/how-to/tracking/#configure-a-project-tracking-session" target="_blank" rel="noopener">relevant QField documentation section&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Snappy QField 3.1 “Borneo” has arrived</title><link>https://qfield.org/2024/01/10/snappy-qfield-3-1-borneo-has-arrived/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 17:11:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2024/01/10/snappy-qfield-3-1-borneo-has-arrived/</guid><description>&lt;p>The launch of QField 3.0 was a big deal, but now we&amp;rsquo;re back to focusing on smaller, more frequent updates. Don&amp;rsquo;t let the shorter change log for 3.1 trick you – there are lots of cool new features in this update!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="main-highlights">Main highlights&lt;/h2>














&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://qfield.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/287987844-8d7c6540-c32c-4d62-bf6e-1636a011567f.png" alt="" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 
 
 >
 
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>One of the main improvements in this release is the brand-new functionality to enable &lt;strong>snapping to common angles&lt;/strong> while digitizing. When enabled, the coordinate cursor will snap to configured angles alongside a visual guideline. This comes in handy when adding new geometries while surveying features with regular angles (e.g. buildings, parking lots, etc.). As QField gets more digitizing functionalities, we’ve taken the time to implement a nifty UI that collapses digitizing toggle buttons into a drawer, &lt;strong>leaving extra space for the map canvas&lt;/strong> to shine through.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 2.8: Boosting field work through external sensors</title><link>https://qfield.org/2023/05/30/qfield-2-8-boosting-field-work-through-external-sensors/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2023/05/30/qfield-2-8-boosting-field-work-through-external-sensors/</guid><description>&lt;p>The latest version of QField is out, featuring as its main new feature sensor handling alongside the usual round of user experience and stability improvements. We simply can’t wait to see the sensor uses you will come up with!&lt;/p>














&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://qfield.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/238116107-1792bb88-9fdb-41e7-9716-7fd65f8837ce.png" alt="" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 
 
 >
 
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h2 id="the-main-highlight-sensors">&lt;strong>The main highlight: sensors&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>QField 2.8 ships with &lt;strong>out-of-the-box handling of external sensor streams&lt;/strong> over TCP, UDP, and serial port. The functionality allows for data captured through instruments – such as geiger counter, decibel sensor, CO detector, etc. - to be visualized and manipulated within QField itself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Capturing more while in the field with the new QField 2.7</title><link>https://qfield.org/2023/04/04/capturing-more-while-in-the-field-with-the-new-qfield-2-7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 04:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2023/04/04/capturing-more-while-in-the-field-with-the-new-qfield-2-7/</guid><description>&lt;p>A brand new version of QField has been released, &lt;strong>packed with features&lt;/strong> that will make you fall in love with this essential open source tool all over again with a focus on capturing more while you are in the field. QField 2.7 nicknamed “Heroic Hedgehog” also includes a number of worthy fixes making it a crucial update to get.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="new-recording-capabilities">New recording capabilities&lt;/h2>














&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://qfield.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/224213255-e51e619a-2505-49dc-a03d-088bfa2530e4.png" alt="" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 
 
 >
 
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The highlight of QField 2.7 is the &lt;strong>new audio and video recording capability straight from the feature form&lt;/strong>. In addition to preexisting still photo capture, this functionality allows for video motion and audio clips to be added as attachments to feature attributes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 2.6: perfecting high-accuracy positioning</title><link>https://qfield.org/2023/01/26/qfield-2-6-perfecting-high-accuracy-positioning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 06:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2023/01/26/qfield-2-6-perfecting-high-accuracy-positioning/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s only been a few weeks into the new year, but we’ve got great news for you: a brand new QField 2.6 “Geeky Gecko ?” has been released with a focus on positioning improvements, including Bluetooth support for Windows. And with that, we are delighted to remove the ‘beta’ status from QField for Windows.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="new-positioning-features">New positioning features&lt;/h2>














&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://qfield.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/26%5Fcover.png" alt="" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 
 
 >
 
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Let’s open with a bang: QField 2.6 now supports NMEA streaming from external GNSS devices over TCP, UDP, and serial ports, in addition to preexisting Bluetooth connectivity.&lt;/strong> This new functionality means that QField is now compatible with a much larger range of GNSS devices out there.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to contribute to QField</title><link>https://qfield.org/2022/12/06/how-to-contribute-to-qfield/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 05:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2022/12/06/how-to-contribute-to-qfield/</guid><description>&lt;p>QField is a community-driven open-source project. It is free to share, use and modify and it will stay like that. The very essence of a community is to help and support each other. And that&amp;rsquo;s where YOU come into play. To make it work we need your support!&lt;/p>














&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://qfield.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/QField%5FAppAward%5F12-2022.png" alt="" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 
 
 >
 
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>For those who don’t know much about the concept of open source projects, a bit of background. Investing in open-source projects is a technical and ethical decision for OPENGIS.ch. Open source is a technological advantage, as we receive input from many developers worldwide who are motivated to work out the best possible software. It prevents our customers from vendor lock-in and allows complete ownership and control of the developed software. And finally, not only financially independent businesses and people should benefit from professional software but also those who might not have the financial means to pay for features, and licences.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 2.5 is here, reaching new heights</title><link>https://qfield.org/2022/11/14/qfield-2-5-is-here-reaching-new-heights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 09:37:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2022/11/14/qfield-2-5-is-here-reaching-new-heights/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our ninjas have been so busy that less than a month after we released QField 2.4, we find ourselves with so many new features we simply can&amp;rsquo;t wait any longer to present to you the latest version of QField: 2.5 &amp;ldquo;Fancy Flamingo ?”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Exciting new features&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>














&lt;figure class="figure text-center mb-4">
 
 &lt;img src="https://qfield.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/25.png" alt="" class="figure-img img-fluid gallery-img"
 
 
 >
 
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>QField’s main new feature of this 2.5 release cycle is its brand new elevation profiling functionality which has been added to the measuring tool. Users are now able to dynamically build and analyze elevation profiles wherever they are - in the field or on their desktop - by simply drawing paths onto their maps and projects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Best of Swiss Enterprise App Award for QField</title><link>https://qfield.org/2022/11/03/best-of-swiss-enterprise-app-award-for-qfield/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 13:02:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2022/11/03/best-of-swiss-enterprise-app-award-for-qfield/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>What a night it was. The &amp;ldquo;Best of Swiss Apps Awards&amp;rdquo; took place in Zurich yesterday, November 2, 2022. We were also nominated with &lt;a href="https://qfield.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">QField&lt;/a>. And in the enterprise category, the app was so convincing, that it was awarded the highest possible price. So it brought the award &amp;ldquo;Best of Swiss Enterprise App&amp;rdquo; home to Graubünden. And as cherry on the cake: QField was also nominated as finalist in the UX/UI category!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 2.4 is here, and it is ?icious</title><link>https://qfield.org/2022/10/13/qfield-2-4-is-here-and-it-is-%F0%9F%8D%8Ficious/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 06:19:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2022/10/13/qfield-2-4-is-here-and-it-is-%F0%9F%8D%8Ficious/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yes, QField for QGIS, the leading fieldwork app, was released on the iOS App Store!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://qfield.org/get" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;img src="https://qfield.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/stores.png" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Get It now for &lt;a href="https://qfield.org/get" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Android, iOS, MacOS, Windows and Linux&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Good things take time (and &lt;a href="https://docs.qfield.org/get-started/sponsor/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sponsors&lt;/a>), and we wanted our Apple users to enjoy the same solid and seamless experience as our Android users. So we took the time needed and ran beta testing of QField for multiple months. Thanks to all the community feedback and to the uncountable work hours put in by our development team, today we released QField on the iOS Appstore.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A New Trick up QField’s Sleeve: Animated Maps</title><link>https://qfield.org/2022/08/16/a-new-trick-up-qfields-sleeve-animated-maps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 04:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2022/08/16/a-new-trick-up-qfields-sleeve-animated-maps/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Starting with QField 2.2, users can fully rely on animation capabilities that have made their way into QGIS during its last development cycle. This can be a powerful mean to highlight key elements on a map that require special user attention.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The example below demonstrates a scenario where animated raster markers are used to highlight active fires within the visible map extent. Notice how the subtle fire animation helps draw viewers’ eyes to those important markers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField collected data crucial in disaster relief after Tonga’s volcanic eruption</title><link>https://qfield.org/2022/02/02/qfield-data-crucial-in-disaster-relief-after-tongas-volcanic-eruption/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 06:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2022/02/02/qfield-data-crucial-in-disaster-relief-after-tongas-volcanic-eruption/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>For once, it&amp;rsquo;s not an app from the Silicon Valley, but from Laax in the Swiss Alps that made the news. By publishing QField as an open-source app, OPENGIS.ch allows companies, organisations and even countries without the necessary financial means to have the opportunity to benefit from this important data collection app. And it is being used: Over half a million downloads have already been achieved. Now, since the volcanic eruption in Tonga on 15 January 2022, the app of the small Laax-based company is playing a not-unimportant role in disaster response planning.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QFieldCloud now opensource - Happy 10 Years of field mapping with QGIS</title><link>https://qfield.org/2021/06/08/qfieldcloud-now-opensource-happy-10-years-of-field-mapping-with-qgis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2021/06/08/qfieldcloud-now-opensource-happy-10-years-of-field-mapping-with-qgis/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, on QField&amp;rsquo;s 10th anniversary, we&amp;rsquo;re extremely proud to publish the results of over &lt;a href="https://github.com/opengisch/qfieldcloud/graphs/contributors" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18 months&lt;/a> of development and give you &lt;a href="https://github.com/opengisch/qfieldcloud/pull/3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the source code of QFieldCloud&lt;/a> to go and make your awesome adaptations, solutions, and hopefully contributions :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to quickly try it out, head to &lt;a href="https://qfield.cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://qfield.cloud&lt;/a> where our hosted solution is running and secure yourself a spot in the beta program.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>QFieldCloud&amp;rsquo;s unique technology allows your team to focus on what&amp;rsquo;s important, making sure you efficiently get the best field data possible. Thanks to the tight integration with the leading GIS fieldwork app QField, your team will be able to start surveying and digitising data in no time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Powerful and gentle QField 1.8 Selma sneaked in</title><link>https://qfield.org/2021/02/24/powerful-and-gentle-qfield-1-8-selma-sneaked-in/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 06:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2021/02/24/powerful-and-gentle-qfield-1-8-selma-sneaked-in/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Get fieldwork smoothly and nimbly done despite the ice and snow outside. Collect accurate data with freehand digitizing and improved form widgets, use the data from your external GNSS receivers without any third-party apps and enjoy the pleasant usability of QField 1.8 Selma.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year started off hi-speed for us. There&amp;rsquo;s been already a lot of coding, designing and teaching, and we&amp;rsquo;ve thrown ourselves into these things we love to do. And we published another QField release last week that I completely forgot to announce in this blog. But here it is. It&amp;rsquo;s QField 1.8, Selma. And it&amp;rsquo;s packed with cool features.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 1.7 Rockies hits the stage</title><link>https://qfield.org/2020/10/20/qfield-1-7-rockies-hits-the-stage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 07:26:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2020/10/20/qfield-1-7-rockies-hits-the-stage/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Be ready for the cold weather with a smooth coordinate search, filters in the value relation widget, fancy new QML and HTML widgets, enhanced geometry editing functionalities and an expandable legend. Right when Autumn starts, QField 1.7 Rockies hits the stage.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As usual get it now on the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ch.opengis.qfield" target="_blank" rel="noopener">play store&lt;/a> or on &lt;a href="https://github.com/opengisch/QField/releases" target="_blank" rel="noopener">github&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The days are getting shorter and the wind blows colder. It&amp;rsquo;s always good to be in a good company outside while getting your mapping work done. QField will be your reliable companion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 1.6 is out!</title><link>https://qfield.org/2020/08/18/qfield-1-6-is-out/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2020/08/18/qfield-1-6-is-out/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Editing multiple features at the same time, support for stylus pens, dynamic configuration of image names and much more.&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>QField 1.6 Qinling 秦岭 comes packed with awesome new features and an improved user experience.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have been very busy over the last few months working on a new and shiny QField release. We have added many new features that increase efficiency on the field or allow for new workflows. In parallel, we have also been working on ironing out a series of issues and improving the overall user experience to make the app as pleasurable to use as possible. The result is QField 1.6 which has been published now.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 1.4 released - Happy new year</title><link>https://qfield.org/2020/03/03/qfield-1-4-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 06:00:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2020/03/03/qfield-1-4-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>What a year&amp;rsquo;s start! After a very packed December publishing all the &lt;a href="https://qfield.org/qgis-on-the-road/">QGIS on the road videos&lt;/a> and quietly releasing &lt;strong>QField 1.3 - Ben Nevis&lt;/strong> we could have gone and relaxed over the holidays. But since we love QField so much we immediately started working on the next iteration. Now, after an intensive testing period, we are proud to announce the release of &lt;strong>QField 1.4 - Olavtoppen&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Olavtoppen!? yes, the highest point of Bouvet Island, the remotest island on Earth. And sure enough, QField would follow you there!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 1.2 released</title><link>https://qfield.org/2019/10/03/qfield-1-2-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 05:29:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2019/10/03/qfield-1-2-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>After an intensive testing period, we are proud to announce the release of &lt;strong>QField 1.2&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As usual, &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ch.opengis.qfield" target="_blank" rel="noopener">get it on play store&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://github.com/opengisch/QField/releases/tag/v1.2.0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">download it from GitHub.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="qfield-crowdfunding-campaign">QField Crowdfunding Campaign&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before digging into all the new goodness that you will find in QField 1.2, let&amp;rsquo;s get some big &amp;ldquo;Thanks&amp;rdquo; out. What QField currently is was mostly possible &lt;strong>thanks to customer projects&lt;/strong> of which the outcome could be mutualized. Thanks a lot to all of you that agreed open source is all about making things possible together!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QField 1.0 is here</title><link>https://qfield.org/2019/03/28/qfield-1-0-is-here/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 15:34:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qfield.org/2019/03/28/qfield-1-0-is-here/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="lets-get-straight-to-the-point">Let&amp;rsquo;s get straight to the point&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s official, QField for QGIS 1.0 is out!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Get it while it’s hot on the Playstore ( &lt;a href="https://qfield.org/get" target="_blank" rel="noopener">qfield.org/get&lt;/a>) or on &lt;a href="https://github.com/opengisch/QField/releases" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are incredibly pleased and proud of just having released such a jewel and are convinced that, thanks to all its features and conscious design choices, QField will make your field digitizing work much more efficient and pleasant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Packed with loads of useful features like online and offline features digitizing, geometry and attributes editing, attribute search, powerful forms, theme switching, GPS support, camera integration and much more, QField is the powerful tool for those who need to edit on the go and would like to avoid standing in the swamp with a laptop or paper charts.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>