<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on QField - Efficient field work built for QGIS</title>
    <link>https://qfield.org/categories/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on QField - Efficient field work built for QGIS</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 04:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://qfield.org/categories/events/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating community, innovation, and open-source GIS in Sweden - AKA the QGIS user conference 2025</title>
      <link>https://qfield.org/2025/06/25/celebrating-community-innovation-and-open-source-gis-in-sweden-aka-the-qgis-user-conference-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 04:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qfield.org/2025/06/25/celebrating-community-innovation-and-open-source-gis-in-sweden-aka-the-qgis-user-conference-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was such a pleasure to be part of the QGIS User Conference 2025 in Norrköping! The event was extremely well organised — a big thank you to the amazing local team for pulling it all together so smoothly. Personally, it felt special to be back in Sweden, almost 20 years after my Uppsala university days. I truly enjoyed giving the opening keynote and sharing the latest from the QGIS project — and of course, showcasing all the QField greatness we&amp;rsquo;ve been working so hard on 💚&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FOSSGIS 2025 – What a Week!</title>
      <link>https://qfield.org/2025/04/02/fossgis-2025-what-a-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 05:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qfield.org/2025/04/02/fossgis-2025-what-a-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As long time sponsors of FOSSGIS, we stepped up the game this year and became &lt;strong&gt;Platinum Sponsors for FOSSGIS 2025&lt;/strong&gt;. We are proud to be part of a thriving open-source GIS community and to contribute to such a great conference. Here&amp;rsquo;s a recap of everything we were involved in:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-talks--presentations&#34;&gt;🚀 Talks &amp;amp; Presentations&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🌍 QField: New Strategy and Application Potential&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Berit&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Marco&lt;/em&gt; presented how QField, with over 1 million downloads and 350,000 active users, is now recognized as Digital Public Good aligned with the UN Sustainable Development Goals. Marco also shared the vision and mission behind QField’s development — highlighting our commitment to &lt;strong&gt;empowering field teams&lt;/strong&gt; across the globe with &lt;strong&gt;open, user-friendly tools for data collection&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Real-world stories illustrated how QField helps bridge data gaps to support informed, sustainable decision-making.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;👉 &lt;a href=&#34;https://pretalx.com/fossgis2025/talk/3KP98N/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;View talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24th Contributors QGIS Meeting in Firenze 2022</title>
      <link>https://qfield.org/2022/09/08/24th-contributors-qgis-meeting-in-firenze-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qfield.org/2022/09/08/24th-contributors-qgis-meeting-in-firenze-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The international community of QGIS contributors got together in person from 18 to 22 August in parallel to &lt;a href=&#34;https://2022.stateofthemap.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OpenStreetMap State of The Map&lt;/a&gt; event and right before the &lt;a href=&#34;https://2022.foss4g.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FOSS4G&lt;/a&gt;. So there was a lot of &lt;strong&gt;open source geo power&lt;/strong&gt; concentrated in the &lt;strong&gt;beautiful city of Florence&lt;/strong&gt; in those days. It was my first participation and all I knew was that it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be an unconference. This means, there is no strict schedule but space and opportunity for everyone to present their work or team up to discuss and hack on specific tasks to bring the QGIS project to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoBeer #26 in Bern hosted by OPENGIS.ch</title>
      <link>https://qfield.org/2019/03/25/geobeer-26-in-bern-hosted-by-opengis-ch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 09:22:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qfield.org/2019/03/25/geobeer-26-in-bern-hosted-by-opengis-ch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Thursday around half past six in the evening. Striking many Geo-scientist found the way to the Spitalgasse in Bern. The reason was the 26th GeoBeer event taking place at [ImpactHub](https:// &lt;a href=&#34;https://bern.impacthub.net/%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://bern.impacthub.net/)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;[GeoBeer](https:// &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.geobeer.ch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.geobeer.ch&lt;/a&gt;) is a quarterly meeting of people interested in geography, GIS, cartography and the latest technologies. It&amp;rsquo;s hosted every time by someone else. This time by us, OPENGIS.ch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure text-center mb-4&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/new.opengis.ch/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/MG%5F3642.jpg?fit=664%2C443&amp;amp;ssl=1&#34;&#xA;         alt=&#34;&#34; &#xA;         class=&#34;figure-img img-fluid gallery-img&#34;&#xA;         loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Right after the arriving, the organizers of GeoBeer Switzerland showed us some funny statistics about the GeoBeer participants since the very first GeoBeer event six years ago.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Marco Bernasocchi then welcomed everyone and introduced our company. We had three speakers this time. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bfh.ch/ti/de/ueber-das-ti/personen/5b7eblnby2di/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Marcus Hudritsch&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bfh_hesb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Berner Fachhochschule&lt;/a&gt; started by presenting the implementation of the visualization of historical buildings, that do not exist anymore in reality. But still, do in virtual reality… No sorry, it&amp;rsquo;s augmented reality. Marcus Hundritsch explained to us clearly the difference between AR and VR and presented some projects they made. [Pascal Bourquin](https:// &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BourquinPascal&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/BourquinPascal&lt;/a&gt;) changed perspective completely by telling us about his project (La Vie en Jaune) to cover all the hiking trails of Switzerland - he logs every trail done on a [map with photographs](https:// &lt;a href=&#34;https://map.lavieenjaune.ch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://map.lavieenjaune.ch/&lt;/a&gt; ). The final speaker was &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dani_viga&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Daniele Viganò&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/gem_devs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Global Earthquake Model Foundation&lt;/a&gt; talking about their challenges of calculating a global model of earthquake hazard, risk and exposure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
